Darren Labithiotis

Remote Senior Software Engineer

darren@labithiotis.com (+44) 7545 615129 Alexanderhofstraße 36, Millstatt, 9872, Austria

I'm a passionate software engineer, with over 10+ years of experience. My experience ranges from building one pagers, full-stacks, single page application, to mobile apps with React Native. I've used various libraries over the years, in particular: Javascript, Typescript, React, React Native, Redux, Sass/Less, Node, Express/Koa, MongoDb, SQL, along with a fairly deep knowledge of DevOps on the AWS and GCP platforms. My current working preference is Typescript and React.

Before becoming a software engineer I studied and worked as a game designer, thus am proficient in Photoshop and Sketch. These skills, combined with my coding ability, help me to deliver projects to a high standard and I have a keen eye for detail and UX.

In 2017 I decided to relocate to the Austrian mountains, moving away from central London where I'd lived and worked for 10 years. Since then, I have been working as full-time remote contractor.

Working remotely genuinely allows me to stay more focused with less distractions, and with modern technology I've easily able to attend meetings, daily stand-ups and pair programming as if I was co-located.

Skills

Agile Pair Programming, TDD, Kanban, Sprints, Retros, Measure to iterate.

Languages Typescript, JavaScript ES5/ES6, JSX, HTML, CSS, Less/Sass, Node, NoSQL, SQL, Bash, Terraform.

Libraries React, React Native, Styled-Components, Redux, Jest, Mocha, Backbone, jQuery, Express, Koa, Underscore/Lodash, Handlebars, Jade, Moment, Numeral, Bootstrap, AWS, MongoDb, MySQL, PostGres, Redis, Webpack, Parcel.

Tools Webstorm, VSCode, Sketch, Photoshop, Slack, Asana, Jira, Miro, Browserstack, Looker, MixPanel, Segment, StatHat, DataDog, Rollbar, CircleCi, TeamViewer.

Employment

Senior Software Engineer @ Triptease

(contractor) April 2016 - Present

I've worked across the range of products Triptease offers. From their price check widget to the backend services for acquiring prices from online travel agents, to the back office platform for hoteliers to manage and review how well their Triptease products performed.

React Native Mobile App - SC Field Guide

https://apple.co/2JJTjlc Jan 2016

I built a React Native mobile app for a highly anticipated game, Star Citizen. Built in my spare time to fill the gap where there was limited apps in the market to provide info for this game.

Fullstack Developer as Contractor @ Prism Digital

(contractor) July 2015 - Present

Solely built a full-stack website using Node, Express, Jade, MongoDB for a recruitment website

Head of Development @ Boppl

April 2013 - April 2016

Hands on developer while managing a team of developers, from Java backenders' to iOS / Android devs while building Boppl's CMS for their mobile ordering platform. The CMS was built using Backbone, jQuery, Handlebars, Require.js plus others.

Software Artist & Project Management @ Waterfront

February 2009 - February 2013

Created and managed the development of lots of highly branded games for a STB company.

Education

- 1st Class Hons (BSc) in Computer Games Design 2005 2008 Staffordshire University
- MongoDB Certified Certificate 2015 MongoDB University

Language

Native English Speaker and learning German